Look up a little.
視線稍微往上看
Now, turn a little this way.
接著面向這邊
It's a little embarrassing
真是害羞
for someone like me to be on the cover of a working mom special issue.
像我這樣的人竟能登上 在職媽媽特輯的封面
There are others, you know?
不是只有我而已喔
Employees younger than me who are raising kids all on their own.
公司裡還有比我更年輕 獨自扶養孩子的員工
-Look, it's Mommy! -Machato!
-你看，媽媽來囉！ -阿正！
The mood of the office changed.
公司內部的氣氛變了
I'm getting the right amount of support that I really need.
能提供我適當的協助 而且是我真正需要的
-Okay. -Look at the camera!
-好 -看鏡頭喔！
"Calling me Joan of Arc is an exaggeration."
“‘說我是聖女貞德就太誇張了啦
"Laughter in parentheses."
括號，笑
"But I want to keep doing my part as an experienced mom."
從今以後我也想盡 作為前輩在職媽媽的職責’
"Inushima's eyes were set on a bright future."
犬島小姐的雙眼正望向閃耀的未來”
What do you think?
你覺得怎麼樣？
I feel proud of her.
我為她感到驕傲
Please read this part.
你把這幾句話唸出來
Hm?
嗯？
"I know a female employee who is planning and trying to conceive."
“我身邊也有計劃性 在備孕的女性員工
-"Here's what…" -…what I want to say.
-我想對對方說的是…” -我想對對方說的是
It's normal for life
人生不如意
to not go the way you plan.
是理所當然的
So I think it's important to have an open heart and go with the flow.
我認為有時候可以順其自然 讓心態寬和一點
And take things lightheartedly.
有著從容的心情比較好
This is harassment?
這樣哪裡騷擾到你了？
She's talking about me.
她說的就是我
-Oh, yeah? -Definitely.
-哦，是嗎？ -絕對是
She's the only one I confided in about trying for a baby.
因為我在備孕的事只有告訴犬島前輩
This is
我這樣算是
outing, isn't it?
被她爆料了吧？
O-Ou…?
“被”什麼？
Outing.
“被爆料”
Revealing someone's gender identity or private information
“在未經本人同意下
I keep learning new words, but there's always more.
這些新詞怎麼記都記不完啊
Unforgivable!
我絕不原諒！
This is maternity harassment!
那樣算是孕婦騷擾吧！
"Lightheartedly"? Get real!
“從容的心情”？開什麼玩笑！
This isn't a lighthearted matter for me!
我可不是抱著好玩的心態啊！
Sorry.
不好意思
I'm shocked.
令我大受打擊
I didn't intend to single anyone out.
我說那些話又不是針對誰
Let alone engage in maternity harassment.
更別說是孕婦騷擾了
In that case, you should watch your words a bit.
如果是這樣，你說話要小心一點
It's been bothering me for a while.
我之前就覺得
You can be a little harsh sometimes.
你有時說出來的話比較不留情
Huh?!
啥？
That expression!
就是這張表情！
It's just like Junko's.
跟純子一模一樣
I don't feel respected.
完全感受不到尊敬
I don't want to hear that from you, Grandpa.
你才沒資格說我呢，外公
Even you calling me "Grandpa" can be taken two ways.
就連這句“外公” 可能單純是在稱呼親人
Do you mean I'm your actual grandfather or just an old man?
也可能是刻意罵我老 兩種觀感完全不一樣喔
I see.
明白了
Next time I see Sugiyama, I'll apologize.
下次看到杉山，我會跟她道歉
Wait,
話說回來
isn't that risky?
你那樣有點不妥吧？
Huh?
什麼？
Oh, right.
哦，對耶
She might press charges against you, Mr. Ogawa.
換你要被指控了，小川先生
Me?
我嗎？
But why?
為什麼？
Confidentiality.
因為你有保密義務啊
Counselors aren't supposed to discuss their clients with outsiders.
諮商師不能對外洩漏這種事啦
But you're family, so naturally, I'd tell you.
我當然要說啊，你是我的家人耶
You know what, people keep way too many secrets.
說起來，人們保密的事太多了啦
If you're trying for a baby, don't hide it. Be open about it.
備孕幹嘛偷偷摸摸？ 光明正大去做就好啦
"Sorry, I'm heading home to have some hanky-panky with my husband."
“抱歉，我今晚要跟先生 做那檔子事，先回家囉”
-Grandpa. -Right.
-外公 -是
Do you really equate trying to conceive with having hanky-panky?
你是不是以為備孕 就等於做那檔子事？
Am I wrong?
不是嗎？
Less hanky-panky is causing the declining birthrate.
就是因為大家不做才導致少子化吧
Maybe you should face charges.
或許你應該被告一次
It's not that simple, okay?
沒有你想的那麼簡單啦
There's still this notion that if you're trying for a baby,
備孕就無法再升職
you'll be taken off the career track.
大家還是有這種既定印象
That, in itself, is maternity harassment, though.
那才是真正的孕婦騷擾吧
Hey!
喂！
Why have you been glancing at your phone?
你為何從剛剛就一直在偷看手機？
Sorry.
不好意思
This is our company's new matching app.
這是敝公司新推出的交友應用程式
"Un-MAY"?
“命運”？
Wait, are you on the hunt for a spouse?
天哪，你在積極找結婚對象？
No.
不是啦…
I'm just testing the product.
只是幫公司做測試
It's not performing as expected, so they wanted my feedback.
因為營收不太好 公司叫我提供一些意見
I see.
這樣啊
So you're finally getting serious, Akitsu.
秋津終於要認真找對象了
If you tie the knot, I can return to Showa without worries.
你結婚的話，我也能放心回昭和了
I'll install the app too.
我也來安裝吧
The thing about Un-MAY is
命運的特徵
that it incorporates the hyper-matching mode,
包含了“超級屬性模式”
offering better efficiency and value compared to other apps.
所以效率和性價比方面 比其他公司的應用程式優秀
Hyper-matching?
“屬性”？
By finely tuning your preferences for age, gender identity, education,
透過詳細分類使用者年齡 性別認同、最終學歷
yearly income, personality, hobbies, favorite places,
年收、個性、興趣、想去的店家
and even preferred cuts of grilled meat,
甚至是愛吃的燒肉部位等
you can avoid matching with partners who don't align with your preferences.
能事先避免和屬性不合的人配對
But if you already know all that, what's left to talk about if you do match?
要是知道得如此詳細 配對成功之後不會無話可聊嗎？
I got a match!
配對成功！
-What?
-什麼？
I used your photo, Akitsu.
我用了秋津的照片
#JUST_WANT_HANKY-PANKY
（#總之就是想做那檔子事）
Wait a minute, Mr. Ogawa!
你幹嘛啦？小川先生！
Why did you use this picture?
而且為什麼用這張照片啊？
Jeez.
真是的
Nagisa.
小渚
-Oh. -Hey.
-哦 -辛苦了
I watched the second episode.
我看了第二集
Seventeen is incredible!
《17歲》超好看的！
Thanks. We're still shooting the third one.
謝啦，不過第三集還在拍呢
Yikes.
天哪
He gives her the ring on the beach, right?
關於在海邊送戒指的那一幕
And the ring…
那個戒指…
Doesn't fit.
戴不進去
Is that a metaphor? Or was her finger swollen?
那是怎樣？是隱喻嗎？ 只是手指浮腫？
-It's a metaphor. -Oh.
是隱喻啦
Good morning.
早安
That girl is trying for a baby, right?
剛剛那女生在備孕吧？
Hey.
別說了
Even if you know, you shouldn't talk about it.
那種事就算知道也不能說出口吧
She's not keeping it a secret, though.
不過她沒有刻意隱藏此事啊
What, really?
什麼？真的嗎？
FERTILITY RECIPES
（備孕食譜）
Apparently, she bought an apartment in the suburbs to prepare for a kid.
聽說她為了日後照顧小孩 在郊外買了一間公寓
I see.
這樣啊
She's really going for it, huh?
她還真拼命
WHEN WILL YOU COME HOME TONIGHT?
（你今天幾點回家？）
Ever since she was in the drama department,
她從在戲劇組的時候
she'd start trying for a baby as soon as she got a boyfriend.
只要交到男友就會開始備孕
She'd skip catered lunches,
既不吃劇組便當
take unauthorized leaves, and be late to work.
又常常無故曠職和遲到
Wait!
等等！
She bought an apartment and is trying for a baby when she's not married?
你說她沒結婚卻買了公寓 然後備孕？
She's trouble.
超誇張的
When her superior finally talked to her, she made a fuss about it being harassment.
後來上司看不下去，出言提醒 結果她大鬧說被騷擾
That's why she moved to the variety department.
所以才被調到綜藝組
You should be careful.
小渚，你也要小心點
See you.
我先走了
Thanks.
謝謝
MATCHED WITH KYOKO
（與恭子小姐配對成功）
That's the sixth one!
配對上第六個人了！
You got a message from Kyoko, working at a securities firm.
在證券公司上班的 恭子小姐傳訊息來囉
Well? You should narrow them down to one soon.
你想怎麼做？該挑出最佳人選了吧
I won't meet any of them.
我不會見她們啦
Why not?
為什麼啊？
Because the app's flaws are obvious now.
因為這個應用程式顯然有缺陷
You're right.
也是啦
The editing is so heavy-handed
有不少女生照片修過頭
that some of these girls have gone beyond cute.
已經超出可愛的範疇了
Nobody realizes that you're pretending to be me.
沒有人發現你仿冒我的身分
That's why our company's app isn't growing.
所以敝公司的應用程式才無法成長
Then, let's pick one using the Six Poems Game.
不然這樣好了 以六人歌牌遊戲來決定
Living in Kasukabe
“住在春日部
Shiori is an apprentice pastry chef…
工作是甜點師學徒的詩織小姐…”
Mr. Ogawa.
小川先生
Her hobbies are cooking and hot yoga
“興趣是做菜和熱瑜珈”
Is romance really necessary?
人一定要談戀愛嗎？
What even is romance?
說起來，“戀愛”到底是什麼？
Is it the buildup to getting together?
在交往前叫戀愛嗎？
Or is maintaining a relationship?
維持交往關係叫戀愛嗎？
Is it from the moment you get together until you get married?
從交往到結婚前這段期間叫戀愛嗎？
Living in Setagaya…
“住在世田谷…”
I've never fallen for anyone.
我從沒喜歡過別人
No one's like that.
世上沒有那種人啦
Well, I am.
有啊，我就是
You just haven't met your soulmate yet.
只是你還沒遇到真命天女罷了
Seeing a bunch of non-soulmates just to find one is
為了遇到真命天女 要跟一堆不適合的人見面
a waste of time and effort.
太浪費精力跟時間了
Shut up. You're a guy, right?
真囉唆，你是男人吧？
Don't you want hanky-panky?
想做那檔子事吧？
When you want that with someone, is that love?
想做那檔子事的對象 就是喜歡的人嗎？
How would I know?
我哪知道
So annoying!
你搞得我好煩躁
What's this?
這些是什麼啦？
It's fancy food a girl would make for an anniversary.
像女生在紀念日精心製作的料理
It's acqua pazza and kale salad.
是義式水煮魚和羽衣甘藍沙拉
So annoying!
令人不耐煩！
Guys don't cook like this.
男人才不會做這種料理呢
They have chopped tuna and stewed offal.
該端上鮪魚切塊和燉內臟才對
Tell me,
我問你
have you never lost sleep over someone?
當想到某人時會睡不著覺
And dashed out of your room in the dead of night to yell?
在半夜衝出房間大喊
Or squeezed a pillow between your legs and yelled?
或把枕頭夾在雙腿間大喊 你沒這種經驗嗎？
Is that what romance is?
那就是戀愛嗎？
Just give it a try.
別問了，你做一次看看
Clutch a pillow and yell.
夾住枕頭，大叫一聲
Too weak!
才不是那樣！
Louder!
要大喊才行！
Louder.
大聲點
-Hey. -Huh?
-喂 -什麼？
"I Googled the cafe in Oshiage."
“我搜尋了那間位於押上的咖啡廳
"It's a cool retro spot."
風格復古，看起來很棒呢
"Okay, see you at five!"
那就五點見了”
Kyoko, from the securities firm, is coming to Scandal tomorrow!
證券公司的恭子小姐 明天會來緋聞咖啡廳！
I wonder if she's here.
不知道她到了沒
Okay.
好
I'll check first.
我先進去幫你看
Here's your order.
請慢用
Thank you.
謝謝
Would you like some milk?
要加牛奶嗎？
I'll take it black. Thanks.
黑咖啡就好，謝謝
Did you see her?
有看到她嗎？
There's a different woman.
我看到不一樣的女人
Well, everyone enhances their photos.
這個嘛，照片多少都會修美一點
Even her age is different.
年紀也不同
I mean, what year is it?
話說現在是哪一年？
I'm sorry.
對不起
What have you done?
不行啦
You can't come over here.
你怎麼能來這裡？
Hey, Barkeep!
喂，老闆！
Two soda floats, please.
來兩杯冰淇淋汽水
This is Akitsu, by the way.
對了，他是秋津
You're Ms. Sakae Sakisaka,
你是向坂紗加惠小姐吧？
the feminist.
那位女性主義者
I can't live without depending on a man.
像我這種人，不依賴男人就活不下去
Like the woman In the Realm of the Senses.
就像《感官世界》裡不檢點的女人
Wait, what happened?
等等，到底發生什麼事了？
You've become pretty too.
解釋清楚吧，竟然還變漂亮了
Thank you.
謝謝
Not a compliment.
不是在誇你
The teacher from Class B, Grade 3,
我和3年B班的安森老師…
The guy with the 90-centimeter inseam. What about him?
從胯下到褲腳長度 有90公分的安森怎麼了？
I…
我跟他…
I got to start dating him.
有幸開始交往了
Got to, huh?
“有幸開始交往了”是嗎？
See, Akitsu?
看吧，秋津
Leave a guy and a girl, and they get together.
把一對男女放著不管 他們就會自然開始交往
After your divorce, "a hole was left deep in your heart."
你離婚之後
Hey, Barkeep! Hurry up!
我說老闆！動作快啦！
-Two? -Yeah.
-你要兩杯？ -沒錯
Right.
好
Anyway, Kyoko might come soon.
話說恭子小姐快到了
No smartphones, no X,
沒有智慧型手機、沒有X
no DMs or emails.
無法傳私訊或電子郵件
But they more than make up for this lack.
但昭和男性卻用熱情的求愛行動
Oh, the way men court in the Showa era!
彌補了工具的不足！
He ambushed me outside my house without an appointment.
明明沒有約好 回家時卻發現他在我家附近埋伏
Hey, I suddenly felt like seeing you.
嗨，我忽然很想見你
When he wasn't in his usual spot, he covered my eyes from behind.
以為他今天沒來 他卻從後面遮住我的眼睛
Guess who?
猜猜我是誰
Then he hugged me, spun me around,
然後被抱住，讓我轉過身
and patted my head, heedless of the public eye.
毫不顧忌周遭的眼光摸我的頭
He put his arm around me.
環抱我的腰部
When I sprained my ankle, he carried me bridal style.
當我扭到腳就公主抱
He danced,
他不停跳舞
danced some more,
一直跳舞
and enjoyed the salad bar.
吃沙拉吧
I love you more than a salad bar
比起沙拉吧
Take notes, Akitsu.
快做筆記，秋津
This is what love looks like.
喜歡上一個人就會這樣
I'm not sure.
我不太確定耶
Sounds like moral harassment by a stalker.
這只是跟蹤狂的男子在精神騷擾吧
But…
可是啊
I didn't hate it.
我並不討厭
It had been ages since I experienced that,
我很久沒被那樣對待了
and it might be the last.
而且說不定是最後一次
It made me feel like I could stay in Showa forever.
我會覺得一直留在昭和也不錯
Did you have
你們做那檔子事了嗎？
Um, sorry to break in.
抱歉，我插話一下
Kyoko's here.
恭子小姐來了
Forget the excuses, Mrs. Compliance.
不要廢話連篇了，規範大嬸
Just tell me
你們做那檔子事了嗎？
Um, Kyoko is here.
不好意思，恭子小姐來了喔
Hanky-panky?
有做那檔子事？
Wait, this is a love hotel.
等等，這是情趣旅館吧
Did you realize that now?
你現在才發現？
No.
不
It slowly dawned on me
在穿過停車場的布簾時 我就隱約察覺到了
I want to clarify something.
我想要弄清楚
What?
弄清楚什麼？
Whether doing that
想試試在這種地方
in a place like this,
做那種事
will still feel like that.
是否也會有那種感覺
That's a lot of demonstrative pronouns.
太多指示代名詞了吧
I talked to you about Eiji Bando, right?
我有跟你說過板東英二先生的事吧？
Yes.
有
You like his looks, right?
他的長相是你的菜吧？
No, yours.
不，你的長相才是
So until I find something positive about you beyond your looks,
所以在我找到 你除了長相以外的優點前
I imagine you look like Eiji Bando.
要把你的外表想像成板東英二…
I feel silly saying it.
說出口連自己都覺得蠢
Did you find something?
你找到了嗎？
"Did you find something?"
“你找到了嗎？”
What's with your self-esteem?
你那種自信是哪來的？
Sushizanmai?
壽司三昧的招牌動作？
You throw me off.
你總是打亂我的步調
I don't understand you.
我實在搞不懂你
Are you conservative, gentlemanly, wild,
到底是保守、紳士，還是狂野？
kind, or calculating?
是溫柔，還是精於算計？
Do you need to put me
你一定要把我分類嗎？
I think
我認為啊
you're a lovely woman, Sakae.
紗加惠小姐是非常有魅力的女性
I love how you're cool, intense, cute, and gallant.
不管是酷酷的、激動的、可愛的
-Everything-- -Stop it.
-或有威嚴的你，全都… -別說了！
Keep going.
繼續說
Because all of those are
全都是構成你這個人的重要元素
Actually, stop.
還是別說了
If you're too affirming, I'll feel like denying them.
被你如此盛讚的話，我會想否認的
And of course,
而且啊
I love your looks too.
我當然也喜歡你的長相
Me too.
我也是
I love you, even if you're Eiji Bando.
就算你是板東英二，我還是喜歡你
-Huh? -Well…
-什麼東西？ -那個…
-It's nothing.
-那是什麼？ -沒什麼
-Huh?!
-怎麼了？ -沒事啦
-C-- -What?
-彩… -什麼？
A Color Timer?
是彩色計時器？
No, it's not.
不是啦，你誤會了
Ugh.
搞什麼？
-Hello? -It's me.
-喂？ -是我
There's been a problem.
發生重大問題了
Come back now.
你馬上回來
It's not easy to be bad, is it?
要做壞事並不容易呢
You weren't being bad.
這不是壞事啊
You're single now, after all. Right, Akitsu?
反正你現在單身，對吧？秋津
He left with the woman.
他跟那個女生一起離開了
What? That bastard!
什麼？那混蛋小子！
Ugh!
真可惜！
I should've had icchome before coming back.
至少該做個一次再回來
"Icchome"?
“做個一次”？
Like "Wow, Higashimurayama"?
被你講得像“哇，東村山”
Wait a minute.
等等
This isn't funny.
這不好笑
Where's Kiyoshi?
阿清呢？
Is he home with Junko?
跟純子在家裡嗎？
It's like something from Tonda Couple.
就像《飛翔的情侶》的情境
This is bad! They can have all the hanky-panky they want!
不行啦！他們可以 做那檔子事做到飽了！
I left a note, so it's okay.
我有留下字條，沒問題的
Besides, she's busy studying for her exam.
而且純子正忙著準備升學考試
She is?
你說純子？
Junko!
純子學姐…
Help me.
大事不好了！
What's that?
那是什麼啦？
Murasaki Shikibu?
紫式部？
It's the note Mom left.
是我媽留的字條
Um, read this part.
那個，你看這裡
Kiyoshi, this is what you must do while you're in Showa.
阿清，你留在昭和該做的任務
You must bring your father together with your mother.
就是替爸爸和媽媽牽線
Are you listening?
你有在聽嗎？
Unless you two meet,
你們如果沒有相遇
I won't exist.
我就不會出生了
You can't expect me to believe you.
一時之間很難相信呢
-This isn't Back to the Future. -Welcome.
-又不是在演《回到未來》 -歡迎光臨
I've brought her.
我把她帶來了
Nice to meet you.
很高興認識你
I'm Sakae Sakisaka.
我是向坂紗加惠
Sakae.
紗加惠
Okay.
好
You should say hi, at least.
你好歹也打個招呼吧
She's come all the way from Matsudo.
人家特地從松戶過來耶
A kid from elementary school?
她只是個小學生嘛
I only feel romantically attracted to someone older than me.
我只喜歡年紀比我大的
Ugh.
真是的
This sucks.
太失望了
I even used Dep to stiffen my hair.
虧我還特地用髮膠做造型
True.
真的耶
Your hair is gleaming.
頭髮油油亮亮的
Saying you're only into someone older is
只想跟年長的人交往
like admitting you're unreliable.
等於承認自己不可靠
It's obvious you want someone to pamper you and it's really lame.
顯然只是要對方縱容你 勸你還是別丟人現眼了
She's really Sakae.
果然是紗加惠小姐
In the first place,
說起來啊
the fact you're concerned about age
會在意對方的年紀
shows you're not seeking an equal partnership.
就代表你根本不追求平等的關係
I bet you see women as accessories for men.
只把女人當成男人身邊的裝飾
The only older woman who'd put up with that nonsense is
能夠接受那種幼稚想法的年長女性
probably your mom.
大概只有你媽媽而已
So why don't you go home and get her to pamper you?
那你還是回家跟媽媽撒嬌吧
What you did was uncalled-for.
你不能做這種多餘的事啦
How many times do I have to tell you?
我說過很多次吧？
Time paradoxes are off-limits.
要避免時間悖論啊
Our first meeting was supposed to be
說起來，我跟你認識
at the local government's matchmaking event.
是在地方政府辦的相親派對上吧
Yes, you're right.
對啦，你說的對
It won't be a "nice to meet you" situation.
到時候就不是初次見面了
Seriously.
真是的
You've become pretty too.
還變得這麼漂亮
Want me to tell you why?
我來告訴你原因吧
Anyway,
這不重要啦
what's the problem you mentioned?
所以到底發生什麼重大問題？
Truth is,
其實…
our sponsor backed out.
贊助商收回資金了
Jason?
你說傑森嗎？
There's a mail-order company in Shanghai.
對方是一間位於上海的網路購物公司
The CEO is a Chinese-American named Jason Chen.
公司的執行長 華裔美國人陳傑森發表聲明
What does it say?
上面寫了什麼？
He's pulling out of the time machine business
他說因為業績不佳
because his company isn't performing well.
將退出時光機事業
That means…
也就是說…
What?
什麼？
I can't run
不能再運行時光機了
I'm sorry.
非常抱歉
The time machine is over
時光機已經不能搭了
I got it. No need to sing.
不用唱我也聽得懂
That was a close call.
好險回來了
What do you mean? What about Kiyoshi?
什麼好險？那阿清怎麼辦？
I can't stay here forever either.
我也不能一直待在這裡啊
No, this won't do, Inoue.
這樣不行，井上
Do something, I beg you.
你想想辦法，哭著求你最後一次
I feel like begging myself.
想哭的是我吧
I didn't even get to take a single trip.
我連一次都沒搭過耶
How much?
要多少錢？
I'll pay 2… No, 30,000.
我看看，我願意出兩萬…
A single trip costs a few million just for the fuel.
一次運行光燃料費就要花幾百萬圓
Of course.
仔細想想確實如此
I was starting to get used to it,
雖然最近搭得很習慣
and I was seeing it like some sort of long-distance bus.
當成在搭長途巴士
But it's a time machine.
但那可是時光機啊
If I can't go back to Showa,
要是我不能回昭和
that means I won't have to die.
就不用死了？
No, what about Junko?
不行啊，那純子怎麼辦？
I can't survive without her. Stupid!
只有我活下來有什麼用？蠢貨！
That time,
在那時候
I managed to travel without the time machine.
我沒有搭時光機就穿越時空了
Ow!
好痛！
I don't think this will work.
怎樣都不覺得可行
There isn't enough precedent.
成功經驗太少了
What are you doing?!
你在幹什麼？
Ow!
痛死我了！
What year is it?
現在是哪一年？
Stop messing around and come with me.
別開玩笑了，快跟我來
Nagisa Inushima has been called in on suspicion of power harassment.
犬島渚因為職權騷擾被傳喚了
What?!
什麼？
We'll be filming this just in case.
保險起見，會錄影喔
This is Ms. Sugiyama's lawyer.
這位是杉山小姐的律師
Have you told Ms. Sugiyama to work extra hours
你是否明知她正在備孕 還要求她加班？
I don't believe I have.
我不認自己做過那樣的事
There are three assistant producers, including her,
因為助理導播包含她共有三人
so I schedule the shifts by talking to them.
我都會跟那三人討論排班方式
May I?
可以問個問題嗎？
Do the other two assistants know she's trying for a baby?
其餘兩人知道她正在備孕嗎？
I think they're pretending not to know.
那兩人應該是假裝不知情
Trying for a baby is pretty sensitive stuff, after all.
畢竟備孕是個敏感話題
Have you suggested any clinics or supplements to her?
你曾經推薦過 診所或保健食品給她嗎？
I only wanted to help.
我是出於好意
I just thought
就只是想說
it must be rough not being able to talk to anyone about it.
她沒有人可以商量，應該不好受
May I?
我可以插句話嗎？
What is it, Mr. Ogawa?
什麼事？小川先生
Don't you think this girl is partly to blame too?
當事人自己也有問題吧？
She was keeping it secret at work, but was dropping hints on social media.
她在公司保密 卻故意在社群帳號留下線索
So people had to tread extra carefully around her.
害大家必須加倍顧慮她的心情
She said the reason she wasn't open about it was to avoid sexual harassment.
她說不公開是為了避免被性騷擾
As feared,
不出所料
after the employee magazine came out, she started receiving slander.
那篇公司內部的報導登出來後 她就開始被人誹謗
That's absurd.
哪有這種蠢事
There's no way to tell if the article was referring to her.
單憑那篇報導，沒辦法確定就是她啊
Can you give us examples?
例如什麼內容呢？
"Hey, Sugiyama, are you getting hanky-panky?"
“嗨，杉山妹妹 有在做那檔子事嗎？”
No way.
不…
"It's a three-day holiday, so three times maybe?"
“有三天連假，可以做個三次呢
"If you're going to do it, do it in the evening."
要做建議在傍晚做
"Sunset on Third Sex, just kidding."
因為《三丁目的夕陽》，開玩笑的”
HE KEEPS MAKING INAPPROPRIATE REMARKS AS HE TIME-TRAVELED FROM 1986
（因他是自1986年穿越時空 有些用詞會不太妥當）
I'm very sorry!
非常抱歉！
So that's why you were a bit on edge.
難怪你坐立不安的樣子
I just couldn't shake off that Showa mindset.
我就是無法擺脫昭和心態
I'm very sorry.
非常抱歉
It's not just you, Mr. Ogawa.
不只有你而已，小川先生
No.
不
In fact, we all have a little Mr. Ogawa inside our hearts,
我們心中都有一個迷你小川先生
and we need to acknowledge and eliminate them.
我們應該承認其存在，並將他驅逐
They tend to multiply if left alone.
放著不管他就會自行增殖
Please don't talk about me like I'm some bad germ.
別把人說得像腸道壞菌嘛
Ms. Sugiyama is having a tough time trying to get pregnant,
杉山小姐的備孕並不順利
and here you are, juggling work and raising your kid.
她覺得一邊育兒一邊工作的你
To her, you seemed like someone who's got it all figured out.
看起來就像擁有一切的成功人士
But…
但是…
And then you made that comment last week.
結果你上週又有不當的發言
You know what I'm referring to, right?
你自己心裡有數吧？
When should we have our next meeting?
下次開會要在什麼時候？
After the broadcast on the 18th?
18日的節目播出之後如何？
Sorry, I have to try for a baby.
抱歉，我那天要備孕
Okay, how about 2 p.m. the following Monday?
那下個週一的下午兩點呢？
I have an appointment with a clinic.
我已經預約了診所
Sorry.
不好意思
How about Tuesday morning or afternoon?
星期二的上午或傍晚呢？
I'm trying for a baby.
不好意思，我要備孕
You don't have to keep saying that.
你不用每次都報備喔
Actually, I think I should.
我覺得反而應該說清楚
I shouldn't take sudden absences.
突然缺席會造成大家的麻煩
In that case,
既然如此
I'll plan the shifts for that week without including you.
那週排班就把你排除在外
You're welcome to join if you can.
你如果能來就來吧
Well, see you after the broadcast.
那就節目播出後見
-Good work. -Thank you.
-辛苦大家了 -辛苦了
"Without including you."
“把你排除在外”
Even you understand, don't you, Mr. Ogawa?
就連小川先生都懂吧？
This falls under pre-maternity harassment.
這構成了孕前騷擾
But that wasn't my intention.
我沒有那個意思
In fact, I was trying to make it easier for her to take time off.
我是想製造出 讓她可以放心請假的氣氛
Women shouldn't feel guilty about trying for a baby.
女性不用因為備孕而感到內疚
Or stress about how men see them--
也不用在意男性的眼光…
I hear you.
我懂你想說什麼
But it doesn't matter if it wasn't your intention.
就算你沒那個意思，也於事無補
You, of all people, should know that.
這點你應該比別人還清楚吧？
Ms. Sugiyama…
杉山小姐她啊
will be taking a break due to a mental breakdown.
因為精神狀態不穩定 而決定暫時不來工作
Nagisa,
小渚
please take
請你也停職一個月
But why?
為什麼？
I messed up way more than she did.
我做的事更糟糕吧
Why am I not being reprimanded?
為什麼不處罰我？
Because I'm a bad germ?
因為我是腸道壞菌嗎？
I understand.
我知道了
Could you…
以下這些話
pass this message to Ms. Sugiyama for me?
請幫我轉達給杉山小姐
I…
我…
don't have it all figured out or anything.
並不是什麼成功人士
I'm still struggling,
現在也還在拼命奮鬥
and I lose many fights too.
一樣老是失敗
I'm a working mom who can't manage without asking for help.
我是個沒有旁人的幫助 就無法工作的在職媽媽
I love my job
我愛工作
and I love my son.
也愛兒子
Those are the only things I can be proud of now.
現在只有這些能讓我引以為傲
But by the time you become a mom,
但是在你當了媽媽之後
I hope I can offer you some support.
我希望能多少幫到你
With what's happened,
希望你不要因為這件事
I don't want you to feel discouraged about trying to conceive.
就對備孕感到消極
I'm not great with words.
雖然我不善言辭
But…
但是…
I'm here for you.
我是站在你這邊的
Excuse me.
我先失陪了
I see.
是喔
You're taking some time off?
你要停職啊？
I've asked Mr. Kurita to cover for me,
有拜託栗田先生代理我的工作
so no worries.
不用擔心
I'm just a stand-in myself.
我也算是代理主持人啦
In the showbiz, you never know when someone else might take your place.
在這個演藝圈 什麼時候會被誰取代都很難說
You're too modest.
別這麼說
You know how you get surprised by new buildings in Shibuya?
當你走在澀谷 經常會驚訝地覺得又蓋了新大樓
But when you try to remember what used to be there,
不過試著回想之前那裡是什麼
it's hard to recall.
總是想不起來
I'll watch your show when it airs.
我會在家收看你的節目
Thanks.
謝囉
-Excuse me. -Uh-huh!
-失陪了 -好！
Let me reintroduce her.
我重新介紹一次
This is Ms. Kyoko Yano from the securities firm.
她是在證券公司工作的矢野恭子小姐
Sorry about this weird old man living with him.
真不好意思 有個奇怪的大叔跟他同居
How many dates have you been on before today?
這是你們第幾次約會？
Dates? Is this a date?
約會？這是在約會嗎？
I'm not sure.
我不確定
I couldn't reserve a table today.
今天來家裡是因為訂不到餐廳
Wait a minute, you two.
等一下，你們兩個
You're formal with each other?
你們用敬語對話？
Yes.
是的
I feel more at ease this way.
我覺得這樣比較自在
Yes, same here.
是的，我也是
Now there are two people who get on my nerves.
令人煩躁的傢伙變成了兩個
Wait,
是怎樣？
so you two aren't a thing?
你們沒在交往嗎？
We matched on the app because we had similar preferences.
我們是在交友應用程式上 因為屬性相似而配對成功
I've never been in love with anyone either.
我也沒有喜歡過別人
But I never have trouble finding a sex partner.
不過上床的對象不知為何卻沒斷過
Why are you nodding, Akitsu?
你點什麼頭？秋津
She's not making any sense.
她剛才說的話很扯耶
A meal partner, a sex partner, a gaming partner…
只是一起吃飯 一起上床，或一起玩遊戲
Having personal time is important.
畢竟獨處的時間很重要
Oh, please.
給我等等…
I'm starting to feel like I'm the weird one.
害我開始覺得是自己有問題
By the way, Ichiro, um…
對了，市郎先生，那個…
How long are you planning to stay here?
你要在這待到什麼時候？
As I've said,
我不是說過了嗎？
until you get married and Nagisacchi returns to the office.
等到你結婚 小渚順利回到工作崗位之後
I'll use the bathroom.
我借一下洗手間
I hate to say this, but…
雖然很難啟齒…
I can make a pretty good guess.
我大概察覺到了
You're welcome to stay here,
我很歡迎你繼續住下去
but I thought it might be awkward for you.
但我怕你會覺得不自在
Welcome.
歡迎啊
I'm sorry
不好意思
for intruding on your family.
要打擾你們父女和樂相處的時間了
She's taking a month-long childcare leave.
產假竟能請到一個月
That's quite swanky of the TV station, no?
電視局還真是有人性
Father, will beer do?
爸，喝啤酒可以嗎？
Yeah.
可以
You're looking good.
你很有精神嘛
Nagisa takes me out for a walk every day,
因為渚每天都帶我去散步
and she even watches my calorie intake.
三餐也幫我控制熱量
Coming.
來了
All right.
好
Machato went to nursery school yesterday,
昨天阿正去了托兒所
so we went to a public bath, right?
我們還一起去超級澡堂，對吧？
I said I'm on childcare leave so he wouldn't worry.
我跟他說是請產假，不然他會擔心
Got it.
我知道了
Huh? Who's that from?
怪了，是誰寄來的？
It's a hometown tax gift.
是故鄉稅的謝禮
What?
什麼？
Could it be…
該不會是…
As I thought, it's from Mr. Yashima.
果然是八嶋先生寄來的
Huh? Snow crabs from Hokkaido.
是什麼？北海道的松葉蟹
That's quite swanky of him!
那傢伙竟然這麼會做人！
He's creepy, so let's toss this.
那傢伙挺噁心的，丟掉吧
No, let's accept it.
不用啦，就收下
It was Four-Eyes being swanky.
這是溫柔眼鏡男的體貼之情
But the three of us can't finish all of this.
不過三個人吃不了這麼多吧
Why don't we invite those two?
把他們也叫來吧
Is that so?
這樣啊
So you're stepping in as Junko's mother.
是你像母親般在幫忙照顧純子
Just while Ichiro is away.
只有市郎先生不在家的時候啦
How is she?
她怎麼樣？
Is Junko doing well?
純子過得好嗎？
Yes.
很好喔
At first, she was puffing away and calling me an old biddy.
雖然她一開始狂抽菸 還叫我“老太婆”
I wanted to give her a spanking.
害我差點揍下去
But she's a really good girl.
但她本性是超乖的孩子
She sure is.
沒錯
She's a good girl.
她真的是個好女孩
Don't cry every time.
不要每次都哭啦
Sorry.
不好意思
It's just…
不過啊
I can't tell if she's real or not, if she's alive or not.
我已經搞不清楚她到底還在不在
It's so confusing.
算是活著還是過世了
I wish I could cry too.
我也很想哭啊
I might never see her again.
說不定再也見不到她了
How was life back in the Showa era?
昭和是什麼感覺？
Everyone talks about the good old days,
大家老是說以前的時代更好
but I'm not so sure.
我常在想到底是不是真的
Because I wasn't born then.
畢竟我當時還沒出生
Let's see.
這個嘛
The food nowadays is definitely better.
現代的食物絕對比較好吃
I agree.
我也覺得
The conveyor belt sushi over here is amazing.
我去這邊的迴轉壽司店吃飯 忍不住叫出聲來
The water is different.
因為水質不同
But that cafe's Napolitan dish…
不過咖啡廳的拿坡里義大利麵…
Scandal's Napolitan doesn't taste the same anymore.
緋聞咖啡廳的拿坡里義大利麵 味道完全不一樣
Absolutely.
沒錯
It tastes worse now. It's soggy and mushy.
變難吃了，麵又濕又軟爛
I think the geezer's grip is failing.
因為那老頭的握力已經衰退了吧
Really? I actually quite enjoy it.
是嗎？我還滿喜歡的啊
You're being fooled.
不，你被騙了
It's almost worth asking for a refund.
難吃到應該叫那老頭退錢
Anything else besides food?
除了食物以外沒別的嗎？
You're a sociologist, aren't you?
你不是社會學家嗎？
They show boobs on terrestrial TV.
無線電視能看到女生胸部
Oh, yeah.
是啊
Nip slips were everywhere!
大家都直接走光呢！
They were happening right and left!
這邊也露，那邊也露！
How embarrassing!
討厭，真不好意思！
Overall, it was quite noisy.
整體來說感覺很吵雜
You mean the streets?
你說街上？
The construction?
是在施工嗎？
No, the people.
不，是人很吵
At the station or supermarket, everyone was chitchatting away.
不論在車站或超市，大家都很多話
Nowadays, people have this and this.
現代的人都愛戴著這些東西
They just look things up instead of asking, so it's quieter.
有不懂的事就上網查 不會去問人，所以比較安靜
I've never considered that before.
我從來沒這樣想過
What about sexual or power harassment?
性騷擾或職權騷擾的狀況呢？
Just terrible.
很嚴重
It's so bad that you have to numb yourself to it.
嚴重到不遲鈍一點根本過不下去
No standards for identifying them either.
也沒有標準可以判定
A society that's a bit insensitive…
可能遲鈍一點的社會
might be easier for me personally.
對我來說比較剛好
I don't think simply identifying harassment helps, though.
不過判定完就結束也沒解決任何事吧
Labeling something as power harassment
判定這是職權騷擾
or moral harassment instead of power harassment.
這不是職權騷擾，而是精神騷擾
By putting them into little categories,
只是透過詳細地分類
people feel like they've addressed the problem.
自以為解決了問題吧
I see.
原來如此
I would've liked to go
若有機會
to Showa.
我真想去看看昭和
That was yummy.
我吃飽了
Inoue,
井上
bring your car tomorrow.
你明天把車開來
What for?
什麼？
Let's all go see Junko.
大家一起去見純子吧
JUNKO INUSHIMA
（犬島純子）
I thought you'd be buried in the Ogawa family's grave.
我還以為她會埋在小川家的墓裡
Sorry about that.
不好意思
Died at 28, huh?
享年28歲啊？
That hurts.
真是令人心痛
But…
不過…
everyone here…
在場的所有人
is connected through Junko.
都跟純子緊緊連結在一起
She's my daughter.
她是我的女兒
My mother.
我的母親
My senior.
我的學姐
My wife.
我的妻子
Right?
沒錯吧？
Please enjoy.
請慢用
Sorry, I wasn't listening.
抱歉，我剛剛沒在聽
I said when you finish high school,
我是說等你高中畢業
let's get married.
我們就結婚吧
No way.
不會吧
So when you said you weren't listening,
所以說，你居然沒在聽
it came as a shock.
我打擊超大的
Sorry.
對不起
I've always admired you
學長是我一直憧憬的對象
and tried to follow in your footsteps.
我總是追著你的背影
And I still like you.
現在也還喜歡你
But…
但是啊
the world is big,
我知道了世界的廣闊
much bigger than your footsteps.
那比學長的後背還寬廣
And I discovered
還存在著各式各樣的活法
there are many ways to live.
我得知了這道理
I learned that too.
我也知道喔
I've taken the bus there, you know.
因為為了追上你
I went after you.
我搭公車去了那邊
To the future?
未來嗎？
Yoasobi,
YOASOBI
Ikinari Steak,
IKINARI STEAK
Takanawa Gateway…
高輪Gateway車站…
I even met Kyon Kyon in her 50s.
我還遇到了50多歲的Kyon Kyon
KYOKO KOIZUMI
（給阿睦先生 小泉恭子）
And yet,
就算這樣
you can still remain true to your own style.
你還是堅持自己的風格
You really are
學長
cool.
你果然很帥氣
Occupation, being hot.
帥哥就是我的職業
Mutchy, that's me.
這就是我，阿睦
I wish you luck.
你要加油喔
Did I just…
難道我…
get dumped?
被甩了嗎？
Sorry I'm late.
抱歉，讓你久等了
I just arrived myself.
我也才剛到
Are you hungry?
你肚子餓了嗎？
No, I'm good.
不，我不餓
-I won't be staying. -Welcome.
-我馬上就走了 -歡迎光臨
-No Napolitan for me, then. -Right.
-我要拿坡里義大利麵 -好的
I mean…
我想說的是…
I realized you weren't it.
我發現你好像不太適合我
Not it?
不適合？
Sorry.
對不起
Do you mean…
是因為…
my preferences?
屬性的問題？
I guess so.
好像是
I don't think I'm as dry as you.
我沒有你那麼冷淡
Should I elaborate?
請問我該說得具體一點嗎？
Yes, please.
麻煩你了
This is our chat yesterday.
像我們昨天的對話
"Sorry, I'm having drinks with my junior."
“抱歉，我跟後輩在喝酒”
"Okay."
“好的”
"Akitsu, do you have an early day tomorrow?"
“秋津，你明天要早起嗎？”
"Yes."
“要喔”
"Sorry."
“不好意思”
"Okay."
“好的”
"I might not make it today."
“我今天可能沒辦法去了”
"Right."
“我想也是”
When I saw it this morning,
我今天早上看到這段對話時
I realized you weren't the one.
就意識到你不適合我
Um…
那個…
Will I marry this guy?
我會想跟這個人結婚嗎？
No.
不會
Especially
最不能接受的
the "Yes" threw me off.
是那句“要喔”
"Do you have an early day tomorrow?" "Yes."
“你明天要早起嗎？”
It's a lazy reply.
回得太隨意了吧
Sorry.
對不起
It's fine. It's just who you are.
沒關係，這就是你的個性
I'm glad it made me realize
很慶幸你讓我察覺到
that I wanted you to feel jealous and be more concerned about me.
我會希望對方吃醋或關心我
I realized I have preferences like that too.
原來我也有這樣的屬性啊
Can't we learn to figure things out as we continue to--
那些可以在交往過程中互相…
No.
我沒辦法
My dream is to marry with zero dating.
因為我的理想是不交往就結婚
Sorry.
抱歉啦
Would you still like the Napolitan?
拿坡里義大利麵還要嗎？
Oh, hey.
哦，你好啊
Akitsu.
秋津
We did it.
謝天謝地
I can go home.
我可以回去了
We found backup fuel for the time machine in the lab at the university.
我們在大學的實驗室裡 找到時光機的備用燃料
Enough for one round trip only.
只剩下來回一趟的量
KYOKO YANO YOU HAVE BEEN BLOCKED
（矢野恭子 你已被封鎖）
So,
所以啊
when you get married and Nagisacchi returns to work…
等你順利結婚，小渚回歸工作崗位…
Stay here forever.
請你一直待在這裡
What?
什麼？
So this is how it feels.
原來是這種感覺啊
What's wrong, Akitsu?
你怎麼了？秋津
Any song will do.
隨便哪首都好
Please sing me a breakup song.
請唱失戀的歌給我聽
Then it has to be "Restaurant."
失戀當然得聽《餐廳》啊
Hey, Barkeep! Hurry!
我說啊，老闆！快點歌！
Right.
好
I just realized something.
我現在才發現
I was in love
原來我喜歡恭子小姐
So this is what it feels like
原來喜歡一個人
to be in love.
是這種感覺啊
"SHITSUREN RESTAURANT"
（《失戀餐廳》）
Not that one.
這不是我想聽的
I want one that goes, "Even though I know you're not here."
我想要那種唱 “她已經不在這了”的失戀歌
Those songs should hit home right now.
現在一定每句都能感同身受
I'll give them my full attention.
我會集中精神聽
Junko!
純子！
Jun--
純…
Kyoko!
恭子！
You're not listening, are you?
你沒在聽吧？
This tastes awful!
好難吃！
-Good morning.
-早安
It's Thursday, right?
今天是星期四吧？
Good morning.
早安
Ms. Namiki?
並木小姐
Yes?
什麼事？
They won't collect the bottles unless you take off the labels.
寶特瓶的標籤如果不撕掉 清潔隊就不會收走喔
Right.
這樣啊…
Sorry about that.
不好意思
Ms. Namiki?
並木小姐？
But they always take them.
但他們每次都有收走啊
These bottles…
這一袋啊…
are the ones you brought last week.
是你上週丟的
They've been here the whole time, so I took them home,
因為一直沒被收走，我就帶回家
removed the labels, and brought them.
撕掉標籤再拿來丟
Please remove the labels.
就麻煩你配合了
Do you…
你有需要…
Sorry?
什麼？
Do you have to talk down to me like that?
有需要那麼高高在上嗎？
I just made a mistake, like any other person.
是人都會不小心犯錯吧
Don't you ever make mistakes?
你不會不小心嗎？
So you don't?
看來是不會啊？
Hey!
那位小姐！
Pour water.
請你澆水
There you go again.
又來了
That's why you get accused of power harassment.
你就是因為這樣 才會被控告職權騷擾
What do you mean by that?
你這是什麼意思？
You know nothing about my daughter.
你又不瞭解我的女兒
Stop it, Dad.
不要這樣，爸
Nagisa hasn't engaged in power harassment.
渚沒有職權騷擾
Absolutely not.
絕對沒有
Even if,
就算真的…
for some reason,
有個萬一
by some chance, she has,
假如她真的做了
for me,
對我來說
she's my only beloved daughter.
她也是我最珍愛的唯一女兒
I've known her for 34 years.
我34年來都看著她
Don't take one single incident,
你只看到她的一小部分
take it out of context,
少在那邊放大過錯
and label it as power harassment!
片面斷定她職權騷擾！
Don't categorize my daughter
不准你以社會的標準
based on society's standards!
硬是要分類我的女兒是哪種人！
Yuzuru!
阿讓！
By some chance
就算有個萬一
Don't make assumptions
也不要隨意斷定
I don't know where you heard that from
雖然我不知道你是聽誰說的
By some chance
就算有個萬一
Don't make assumptions
也不要隨意斷定
No one knows the full truth
畢竟沒有人知道真相
If, by some chance
就算有個萬一
You happen to be right
你說的是事實
It still doesn't excuse you
也不能當成
From separating your trash
你不做垃圾分類的藉口
Dad!
爸！
Okay. I get it.
我知道了，明白了
No, you don't.
你才不知道
Ever since my wife passed away,
自從我老婆過世之後
Nagisa has been my only family.
我就只剩渚一個家人
What's the matter, Yuzuru?
你怎麼了？阿讓
Hello.
喂？
Please send an ambulance right away.
請幫我緊急派一台救護車
That's enough, Dad.
夠了啦，爸
Even in my current condition,
就算我變得體弱多病
she hasn't abandoned me,
她也沒有拋棄我
and she always stays by my side.
一直陪在我身邊
So don't speak ill
不准你說我女兒的壞話！
Yuzuru!
阿讓！
By some chance
就算有個萬一
Don't judge from one incident
也不要片面斷定
A superior accused of power harassment
職權騷擾的上司
Isn't a demon
不是惡鬼
By some chance
就算有個萬一
Don't judge from one incident
也不要片面斷定
A boss accused of sexual harassment
性騷擾的上司
Is still a human being
也同樣是人啊
Please stop.
別再唱了
The ambulance arrived quickly!
來了！救護車好快就到了！
-Are you okay?
-還好嗎？
Let's help you up.
慢慢扶你起來喔
All right.
來
Slowly.
慢慢來喔
My dear neighbors,
各位鄰居
I apologize for the disturbance.
抱歉驚擾大家了
I'll be away for a while,
我會暫時不在家
but please take care of my dau--
我女兒就拜託大家多多照…
By some chance
就算有個萬一
Don't be offended
也不要覺得受傷
That's not what I intended
她說的話並沒有惡意
You're like James Brown!
你好像詹姆士布朗喔！
Yuzuru, you're like James Brown!
阿讓，你好像詹姆士布朗！
By some chance
就算有個萬一
Don't make assumptions
也不要隨意斷定
No one knows the full truth
畢竟沒有人知道真相
Dad!
爸！
Yuzuru was rushed to the hospital
阿讓緊急住院
and narrowly escaped death.
保住了一條命
Somehow, news of Nagisacchi's harassment leaked
小渚的職權騷擾事件 不知從哪洩漏出去了
and went viral on social media.
在社群媒體被傳開
Nagisacchi,
小渚
let's go see your mother this Saturday.
這個週六我們去見你媽媽吧
You want to visit her grave again?
又要去掃墓嗎？
No.
不
While we're there,
我順便帶你去吃
I'll treat you to some amazing Napolitan.
超好吃的拿坡里義大利麵
What?
什麼？
This is the last trip, right?
但那是最後一次吧？
Subtitle translation by: Ai Matsuoka
字幕翻譯：樊穆妮
I'm Ogawa from Heaven.
我是佛祖小川
No way!
不要！
-The engine started! -I'll give up on the time machine.
-引擎發動了！ -時光機就算了吧
Don't say that!
別那麼說嘛！
"I can't say goodbye."
我無法說再見
"You idiot!"
笨蛋！
It's okay to take better care of yourself.
你該更加重視自己
So I'll never see you again.
我們已經無法再見了
It's my duty as a parent to save my daughter.
救自己的女兒是身為父親的責任